

Nguyen Hoang Thau Senior Frontend Engineer

nghoangthau@gmail.com Skype: hoangthauit627 0366751156

OBJECTIVE

I'm a passionate web developer with over 8 years of experience and more than a year in leading frontend team. I focus on website technologies and have been an avid front-end developer for many years. I love programming and have hands-on experiences with some languages and technologies: JavaScript(ES6), TypeScript, ReactJS, Redux, Styled components, AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, Jquery, JqueryUI, Bootstrap. I'm a quick learner and always want to take new challenges. I have strong experience in React quality coding with maintainable abilities. I'm a big fan of JavaScript and it's really my area of expertise.

EDUCATION

CAN THO UNIVERSITY, VIETNAM

BACHELOR DEGREE OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

2009 - 2013

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJS, Redux, AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, Jquery, JqueryUI, Bootstrap, Styled components for web development.
- Single Page Application, RESTful Web API, GraphQL.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TinvioSenior Frontend Engineer

May. 2022 - Present

Tinvio is built around the idea that every merchant and supplier should be able to work smarter together. The core product is a B2B transactions platform that helps small-medium merchants and suppliers manage orders, invoices, and payments through a chat-led user interface.

When I joined Tinvio, I mainly worked on Dashboard product which provides a performant web app for suppliers and merchants to manage their orders, invoices, chat, inventory, ... In addition, I helped the team build the core features for the product including auth flow and user management module.

My role and responsibilities were as follows:

- Implementing new features (chat broadcast, inventory, invoices, ...) and maintaining existing Dashboard product
- Creating common components with Storybook

- Building the new project from scratch and implementing core features such as auth, user, home, organization flow
- Code review

Technologies Utilized: ReactJS, Redux, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Styled component, RESTful Web API, GraphQL

NVG Dec. 2019 - Apr. 2022

Frontend Lead

NVG is fully part of SMG, pioneering and leading marketplace group in Switzerland. Operating as a R&D hub, we help shaping the Swiss digital future by providing innovative solutions that serve the company purpose.

I've worked on real estate platform Immoscout24.ch which is the leading online marketplace for private and commercial real estate and the trusted address for finding a home in Switzerland.

My role and responsibilities were as follows:

- Leading frontend team at NVG side and help other members to solve technical problems, code review
- Working with PM, PD to clarify requirements and designs
- Building some key features with quick delivery and quality code
- Contributing some ideas to improve performance and codebase
- Coaching, assisting new members and junior developer in the team
- Interviewing new frontend developers for the team

Technologies Utilized: ReactJS, Redux, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Styled component, RESTful Web API

QUOINE Jul. 2018 - Nov.2019

Senior Frontend Engineer

Quoine is a leading fintech company that provides trading, exchange, and next generation financial services powered by blockchain technology. I'm responsible for building new amazing landing pages with performance and SEO optimization. I support marketing team to customize CMS pages to produce responsive marketing pages which turn out to be effective tools to broadcast products to customers. Also I contribute some best practices to refactor current web application.

My role and responsibilities were as follows:

- Analyze the requirement
- Work with design team to create responsive Landing pages
- Work with Marketing team to optimize SEO

Technologies Utilized: ReactJS, Redux, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS

ORIENT SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Senior Frontend Engineer

I've worked on this project for over 2 years. This product was built by advertisers and media companies. They

Oct. 2015 - Jun. 2018

wanted to improve their ability to optimize marketing investments. We found the best way to display data visually through charts, data table, powerful reports, ... We used Highcharts library to present intuitive graphs and significant changes in data. I was responsible for a lot of features in this project such as building charts, exporting reports, data table, data connections,...

My role and responsibilities were as follows:

- Analyze the requirement
- Design UI Mock up
- Coding and unit testing

Technologies Utilized: AngularJS, Angular, NgRx, Bootstrap, jQuery, jQueryUI, HTML5, CSS3, Highcharts, TypeScript.

TMA SOLUTIONS Aug. 2013 - Sep. 2015

Frontend Developer

I joined this project for about 2 years. My customer was Alcatel Lucent. I took responsibility for front-end position on this web application for network management system. In this project, I used AngularJS, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, ... We've built charts and graphs using D3 library. The system was designed to support responsive mobile design as well as support popular web browsers, such as Firefox, IE (10+), Chrome, and Safari.

Technologies Utilized: AngularJS, jQuery, jQueryUI, HTML5, CSS3, D3.